Emmanuel Ezechukwu

Encino, CA 91316 emmanuel.ea@myyahoo.com +1 310 848 0138

Professional Summary

Product and marketing leader with 10+ years of experience across consumer goods, tech, and media. Proven track record in leading high-ROI digital campaigns, scaling product strategies, and integrating AI and data into marketing pipelines

Willing to relocate to: Los Angeles County, CA

Work Experience

Product Manager - Smart Audiences, Integrated Media

Procter & Gamble-Cincinnati, OH May 2022 to Present

Led efforts to enhance ROI for P&G's digital advertising through advanced technical skills. Managed consumer data, advertising, and marketing technologies in collaboration with technology partners, data providers, and internal teams. Developed and implemented audience data strategies tailored to category needs. Collaborated with product and data managers to incorporate AI and ML into data categories. Drove brand automation and consumer data strategy. Leveraged expertise in digital marketing, data management, and analytics to foster best practices and achieve high ROI. Managed data quality, operations, storage, and security. Oversaw social media accounts of popular brands like "Pampers" and "Vicks."

Marketing Manager

The Coca-Cola Company May 2020 to April 2022

Worked as part of the marketing team responsible for several successful marketing campaigns. I worked on the "Share a Coke" campaign, with a focus on bringing the worldwide campaign to the Nigerian and West African consumers. We hit several milestones and surpassed expectations. We accounted for over \$12,000,000 in revenue per marketing campaign. Handled collaborations with social media influencers and led the initial push towards marketing the company's products through internet streamers like Kai Cenat and iShowSpeed in a bid to expand the customer base.

Manager, Digital Marketing

Nestlé USA-Newark, NJ July 2017 to May 2020

Oversaw marketing campaigns for the company's product releases. I was involved in the digital and social media space, while coordinating with the urban team to ensure thematic consonance and a cross-sectional approach. Led a team who generated over 35 percent growth in digital footprint and presence for the company's flagship products in one year, while keeping costs at a minimum. Managed social media accounts for popular company products like "Nescafé" and "KitKat," which entailed content creation, team collaborations, event coverage and customer acquisition.

Project Manager

Lionsgate-Santa Monica, CA May 2015 to June 2017 Handled project design, execution and customer follow-up. I was responsible for ideation, concept creation and culture-market fit.

Worked on the planning, cost assessment and overall execution of over 16 major projects, which amounted to over \$18,000,000 in profit for investors. Handled creative and marketing work for popular projects like "La La Land" starring Ryan Gosling and Emma Stone and "Wonder" starring Julia Roberts and Owen Wilson. Contributed extensively to the ideation, design and execution of several posters, billboards, marketing taglines and campaigns relating to the movies and other media projects released by the studio during this period.

Creative Director

Penguin Random House February 2012 to April 2015

Created concepts and set pieces for perception management and brand-building. I coordinated across an array of different products and generated unique angles for market penetration for each one. I achieved an over 70% success rate with each iteration. Responsible for seeking out ways to market popular classics like "The Great Gatsby" by F. Scott Fitzgerald and "African Stories" by Ben Okri to younger audiences. Utilized emerging social media trends and tied these products into the cultural zeitgeist to foster reading culture and acquire more long-term customers for the company.

Education

Bachelor's degree in Pharmacy

University of Nigeria - Nsukka June 2012 to June 2018

Skills

- Business Analysis (7 years)
- Product development
- Musicianship
- Leadership
- Framer
- Al Prompting (1 year)
- Fund Management (10+ years)
- Pharmacy Technician Experience
- Blockchain Technology (10+ years)
- Artiste & Repertoire
- · Marketing
- Pharmaceutical Care (10+ years)
- Writing skills
- Real Estate Sales (10+ years)
- Video Creation (10+ years)
- Al Art Prompting and Refinement (1 year)
- Community Building (10+ years)
- Analytics
- Product Ideation (8 years)

- · Product strategy
- · Analysis skills
- · Senior leadership
- Brand Improvement (10+ years)
- Singing
- · Social media marketing
- E-commerce (2 years)
- Prospecting (10+ years)
- · Email Marketing
- User Experience (UX) (8 years)
- Windows
- Graphic design (10+ years)
- Vibe-coding (1 year)
- IT
- User Interface (UI) (10+ years)
- Branding (10+ years)
- B2B Sales (10+ years)
- Venture Capital (10+ years)
- · Marketing automation
- Man-Management (10+ years)
- Public Relations
- Blogging
- · Performance marketing
- Mentoring
- Visualization
- Prototyping (8 years)
- Hospitality
- Public Speaking
- Digital Marketing
- · Web Development
- Product management
- Microsoft Office (10+ years)
- Content creation
- Sales
- Social media management
- · Organizational skills
- Bitcoin Blockchain (10+ years)
- Vlogging (4 years)
- · Presentation skills
- Quantitative Analysis (10+ years)

- Acting
- Content Creation
- Video Editing (3 years)
- Solana Blockchain (3 years)
- Prototyping
- Blogging (10+ years)
- Google Ads
- Communication skills
- Google Suite
- Conflict Management (10+ years)
- Team management
- Customer Retention (8 years)
- Al Business Integration (1 year)
- Conflict Resolution (10+ years)
- Innovation
- Shopify (2 years)
- Alpha and Beta Testing (10+ years)
- Research
- Management
- Application Development (10+ years)
- Cash management
- Pharmaceutical Drug Formulation and Preparation (10+ years)
- Man-management
- Business Intelligence (5 years)
- Video Games (10+ years)
- · Email marketing
- · Customer service
- · Digital marketing
- · People Skills
- Streaming (10+ years)
- Operational Analysis (8 years)
- Public relations
- · Medical billing
- Ghostwriting (10+ years)
- Video editing (5 years)
- Business Revival (9 years)
- Workplace Camaraderie (10+ years)
- Cryptocurrencies (10+ years)
- Songwriting
- · Copywriting

- Time management
- Teaching
- · Content Development
- Customer Relationship Management (8 years)
- Negotiation
- Branding
- WordPress
- Ethereum Blockchain (7 years)
- Risk Assessment (10+ years)
- Accounting
- · Affiliate marketing
- · Debits & credits
- Facebook Prospecting (10+ years)
- CRM Software (10+ years)
- Canva (Expert) (7 years)
- Market Research (10+ years)
- Real Estate Development (10+ years)

Links

https://japsonline.com/abstract.php?article_id=2894&sts=2

Certifications and Licenses

Licensed Pharmacist

Present

Licensed to practice Pharmacy by the PCN.

Emergn's Product Management

Present

This comprehensive program deals with the VFQ model by Emergn to provide value fast, optimize the flow of work and ensure steady quality delivery to customers.

California Driver's License

June 2012 to Present

Driver's License